Guide to the Anson Conger Goodyear Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Anson Conger Goodyear Collection
1813-1890
MS 244
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1
(2 boxes)
Correspondence, diaries, proclamations, and drafts of letters chiefly relating to the Civil War, but also including letters from the Jacksonian period. The major portion of the collection concerns the siege of Fort Sumter with letters from both Major Robert Anderson and General P.G.T. Beauregard. Included also are a diary kept by General S. Wylie Crawford during the siege and two letters from Abraham Lincoln. Other portions of the collection concern Lincoln as a political figure; the relations of Jefferson Davis and General Beauregard, with letters by both principals; letters by and about General Sherman; and letters on the controversy between Andrew Jackson and John Randolph, with letters from both.
Goodyear, A. Conger (Anson Conger), 1877-1964
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of A. Conger Goodyear, 1953.
Scope and Contents
This collection of Civil War materials, compiled by Anson C. Goodyear and given to Yale University in 1953, contains correspondence, diaries, proclamations, and other papers relating chiefly to the Civil War but also including letters from the Jacksonian period. The papers are mounted in a series of bound volumes devoted to various subjects. The folder list that follows provides descriptions of the individual items in the order in which they appear in the volumes; an alphabetical index to the items is appended to this register.
The first half of the collection pertains to the siege of Fort Sumter. Included are two diaries kept by General S. Wylie Crawford, surgeon at the Fort. There are also three volumes containing letters and other papers of Abraham Lincoln, Major Robert Anderson, General P.G.T. Beauregard, Gideon Welles, Salmon P. Chase, William Lloyd Garrison, and others.
The second half of the collection covers several topics. Abraham Lincoln's political associates and opinions of Lincoln expressed by Northern and Southern political figures form the subject matter of two volumes. Included are items by Horace Greeley, Mary Todd Lincoln, General Edward S. Bragg, James Garfield, and others. A volume devoted to the relations of Jefferson Davis and General Beauregard follows, containing letters by and about both men, while a further volume contains letters by and about General W.T. Sherman. In these three volumes are letters of Generals Jubal Early, Joseph E. Johnston, Braxton Bragg, and other military figures. The final volume concerns the controversy between Andrew Jackson and John Randolph, and contains items by both men, as well as by Francis Scott Key, Henry Clay, Martin Van Buren, Winfield Scott, and others.
Biographical / Historical
Anson Conger Goodyear, the son of Charles W. Goodyear, was born in Buffalo, N.Y., June 20, 1877, where his father is engaged in the Lumber and Railroad Business. His mother's name is Ella P. (Conger) Goodyear. Anson was equipped with preparatory knowledge at the Nichols School, Buffalo, N.Y.
After graduation, Anson became connected with the Buffalo and Susquehanna Railroad Company, of which he is now Vice-President. He is Second Vice-President of the Great Southern Lumber Company, and Managing Director of the Goodyear Lumber Company, of which his father is Vice-President.
On June 29, 1904, in the City of Buffalo, N.Y., Anson was married to Miss Mary Forman, daughter of Mr. and Mrs. George V. Forman, of Buffalo, N.Y. They have one child, a son, born in Buffalo, N.Y., July 8, 1906, and named George Forman Goodyear.
Index to Correspondents
Anderson, E.B. (Mrs. Robert) folder 4, pp.8-9
Anderson, Robert folder 3, pp.7-11 folder 4, p.7 folder 4, p.26 folder 5
Ashton, Henry folder 10, pp.4-5
Austin, Charles folder 4, p.43
Beauregard, Pierre Gustave Toutant folder 3, pp.12-15 folder 4, pp.18, 25, 27 folder 8, pp.13-14, 29-30
Blair, Montgomery folder 3, pp.16-19
Bonner, John folder 5
Bragg, Braxton folder 9, pp.2-3
Bragg, Edward S. folder 7, p.11
Bright, John folder 7, p.3
Buell, Don Carlos folder 3, pp. 20-23
Campbell, John Archibald folder 4, pp.1-5
Chase, Salmon P. folder 4, p.10
Clay, Henry folder 10, pp.10-11
Crawford, Samuel Wylie folder 1 folder 2 folder 3, p.24 folder 4, pp.20-24
Davis, Jefferson folder 8, pp.2-10
Early, Jubal folder 8, pp.15-24, 47 folder 9, pp.4-5
Evans, Augusta J. folder 8, pp.41-46
Foote, Andrew Hull folder 4, p.37
Fox, Gustavus Vasa folder 3, pp.25-28 folder 4, pp.12-17
Garfield, James Abram folder 6, p.5
Garrison, William Lloyd folder 4, p.49
Gist, States Rights folder 4, p.28
Greeley, Horace folder 6, pp.1, 8 folder 7, p.8
Griffin, L.P. folder 5
Hagood, Johnson folder 8, pp.11-12
Hart, Peter folder 4, p.41
Hatch, Israel Thompson folder 6, p.10
Hawley, Joseph R. folder 4, pp.38-39
Hay, John folder 6, p.2
Hewett, S.C. folder 4, p.50 folder 5
Holt, Joseph folder 3, p.29
Jackson, Andrew folder 10, pp.7, 15-16
Jackson, Rachael (Mrs. Andrew) folder 10, pp. 7-8
Jamison, David Flavel folder 4, p.44
Johnston, Joseph E. folder 8, p.31
Jones, David Rump folder 4, p.11
Jones, James folder 4, p.45
Jordan, Thomas folder 5 folder 8, pp. 32-35 folder 9, pp.6-7
Key, Francis Scott folder 10, pp.3, 6
Lewis, William Berkeley folder 10, p.13
Lincoln, Abraham folder 3, pp.2-4
Lincoln, Mary folder 7, p.10
Magrath, Andrew Gordon folder 4, p.42
Mercer, Samuel folder 4, pp.33-36
Miles, William Porcher folder 3, p.35 folder 4, p.46 folder 8, pp.1, 3
Orr, James L. folder 3, p.34
Pettigrew, James Johnston folder 4, p.32
Pickens, Francis Wilkinson folder 3, pp.30-33 folder 4, p.19
Randolph, John folder 10, p.2
Randolph, Martha (Jefferson) folder 10, p.1
Reed, William folder 10, p.12
Riley, James Whitcomb folder 7, p.7
Ripley, Roswell S. folder 4, p.29
Scott, Winfield folder 10, p.14
Seymour, Horatio folder 6, p.6
Sherman, John folder 6, p.7
Sherman, William Tecumsah folder 9, p.1
Simms, W. Gilmore folder 4, p.6
Smith, Gustavus Woodson folder 4, p.31
Stanton, Edwin McMasters folder 4, p.48
Stevens, Isaac folder 7, p.1
Stoddard, Richard H. folder 7, pp.4-5
Sumner, Charles folder 6, p.9 folder 7, p.9
Sumter, Thomas folder 3, p.1
Trapier, James H. folder 4, p.30
Toucey, Isaac folder 4, p.40
Van Buren, Martin folder 10, p.17
Walker, W.S. folder 8, pp.36-38
Welles, Gideon folder 3, pp.5-6 folder 6, p.4
Wright, Marcus J. folder 8, pp.39-40
Unidentified folder 4, p.471
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Fort Sumter (Charleston, S.C.); Confederate States of America -- Politics and government; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; United States -- Politics and government; Diaries; Anderson, Robert, 1805-1871; Beauregard, G. T. (Gustave Toutant), 1818-1893; Blair, Montgomery, 1813-1883; Buell, Carlos, 1818-1898; Campbell, John Archibald, 1811-1889; Clay, Henry, 1777-1852; Crawford, Samuel Wylie, 1827-1892; Davis, Jefferson, 1808-1889; Early, Jubal A. (Jubal Anderson), 1816-1894; Fox, Gustavus Vasa, 1821-1883; Garfield, James A. (James Abram), 1831-1881; Garrison, William Lloyd, 1805-1879; Goodyear, A. Conger (Anson Conger), 1877-1964; Greeley, Horace, 1811-1872; Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845; Jordan, Thomas, 1819-1895; Key, Francis Scott, 1779-1843; Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865; Lincoln, Mary Todd, 1818-1882; Mercer, Samuel, d. 1862; Pickens, F. W. (Francis Wilkinson), 1805-1869; Randolph, John, 1773-1833; Riley, James Whitcomb, 1849-1916; Scott, Winfield, 1786-1866; Sherman, William T. (William Tecumseh), 1820-1891; Stanton, Edwin M. (Edwin McMasters), 1814-1869; Sumner, Charles, 1811-1874; Sumter, Thomas, 1734-1832; Van Buren, Martin, 1782-1862; Welles, Gideon, 1802-1878
- PAPERS RELATING TO THE SIEGE OF FORT SUMTER, Circa 1813-1890; .75 linear feet (2 boxes)
  - Pocket Diary of General Crawford while in Fort Sumter. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    The first entry is dated February 13, 1861. It continues with daily entries through April 14, 1861 when the fort was evacuated by the Union forces. There are later entries in the diary relating to other matters during the year. In morocco slip case.
  - Original manuscript kept by S. Wylie Crawford during the siege (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Running from September 9 to December 26, 1860, in Fort Moultrie, and from December 26 to April 14, 1861, in Fort Sumter. About 80 closely written pages. Crawford, who later became a general, was surgeon with General Anderson at Fort Moultrie and Fort Sumter.
  - VOLUME I
    - General Thomas Sumter, A.L.S. 2pp. folio, Warsaw, March 9, 1781, to General Greene; fine war letter. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Fort Sumter was named after General Sumter.
    - Abraham Lincoln
      - A.L.S. l p. 8mo., Springfield, Illinois, December 22, 1860, to Major General David Hunter (Box 1, Folder 3)
        Marked confidential in his hand with addressed envelope. Says in part, "If the forts fall, my judgement is that they are to be retaken." Published in volume VI of the complete works on page 86.
      - L.S., Executive Mansion, March 15, 1861 to the Secretary of the Navy (Box 1, Folder 3)
        Inquiring if it is the Secretary's opinion that it would be wise to attempt to provision Fort Sumter. A similar letter was addressed to each member of the Cabinet. See Volume VI of the complete works, page 92; with addressed envelope in Lincoln's hand.
    - Gideon Welles, A.L.S. 4pp. 4to; Navy Department, March 15, 1861, to the President replying to the previous letter addressed to him by the President regarding the provisioning of Fort Sumter. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      See volume VI of Lincoln's complete works, page 203.
    - Major Robert Anderson
      - A.L.S. 4pp. 12mo., Fort Moultrie, S.C., December 19, 1860. To Rev. R.B. Duan with addressed envelope. (Box 1, Folder 3)
        Stating that the fort is a very weak one to be defended, etc.
      - A.L.S. 4pp. 8mo., Fort Sumter, S.C., January 20, 1861, to S.F. Crawford (brother of S.W. Crawford). (Box 1, Folder 3)
        Praising his brother and discussing the situation in the harbor of Charleston.
      - A.L.S. 6pp. 12mo., Fort Sumter, March 11, 1861, to Reverend R.B. Duan. (Box 1, Folder 3)
        Speaking of the policy of the Administration, the occupancy of the fort, etc.; with addressed envelope.
      - A.L. unsigned, 2pp. 8mo. Undated, but probably Fort Sumter March 28, 1861. (Box 1, Folder 3)
        Speaking of demand for reinforcements, the hope that bloodshed may be averted, etc.
      - A.L.S. 3pp. Fort Sumter, March 26, 1861, to General P.G.T. Beauregard. (Box 1, Folder 3)
        The reply to General Beauregard's demand that Fort Sumter be evacuated. States that unless Beauregard's terms are changed he will never leave the Fort alive.
    - General P.G.T. Beauregard
      - A.L.S. 4pp. 12mo., Charleston, April 12, 1861, 2½ PM to Major Whiting in regard to the time of firing on Fort Sumter, the rate of firing. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - A.L.S. 2pp. 8mo., Charleston, April 12 (1861) 2½ P.M. to Major Whiting. (Box 1, Folder 3)
        Written a few hours after the first gun had been fired at Fort Sumter. Cautioning him against firing too rapidly. Says that Anderson has provisions for only four days, etc.
      - General Orders No. 20, Charleston, April 14, 1861. (Box 1, Folder 3)
        Signed by D.R. Jones, of Beauregard's staff. 2pp. 4to, regarding the surrender of Sumter. Congratulating the troops upon their success.
    - Montgomery Blair
      - A.L.S. 2pp. 8mo., Washington, April 28, 1882, to General Crawford. (Box 1, Folder 3)
        Referring to Fort Sumter and speaking very strongly of Seward's purpose to "surrender the Union."
      - A.L.S. 2pp. 8mo., Washington, June 6, 1882, to General Crawford (Box 1, Folder 3)
        Referring to Fort Sumter and the Cabinet meeting held to discuss what should be done immediately following Lincoln's Inauguration.
      - A.L.S. 2pp. 8mo., addressed to General Crawford regarding reinforcements for Fort Sumter, a cabinet meeting, etc. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Don Carlos Buell
      - A.L.S. 20pp. Airdrie, January 12, 1884, to General Crawford (Box 1, Folder 3)
        Giving the history of the order carried by General Buell from Washington to Major Anderson at Fort Moultrie in December 1860. This order was given verbally to General Buell by the Secretary of War for transmittal to Major Anderson.
      - A.L.S. 5pp. 12mo., Airdrie, February 4, 1884 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        Amplifying his statements in the previous letter.
      - A.L.S. 8pp. 12mo., Airdrie, February 18, 1884 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        Additional details amplifying the preceding two letters.
    - General S. Wylie Crawford, A.L.S. April 13, (1861). (Box 1, Folder 3)
      An account of the bombardment of Fort Sumter and the negotiations that lead up to it. Written during the bombardment on the date preceding the evacuation.
    - Gustavus Vasa Fox
      - A.L.S. 1p. 8mo., Washington, February 8, 1882 to General Crawford (Box 1, Folder 3)
        Saying he is sending his account of his connection with the Fort Sumter expedition.
      - A.L.S. 3pp., Washington, April 25, 1882 to General Crawford (Box 1, Folder 3)
        Containing reference to the plans for the relief of Fort Sumter with mention of Lincoln, Holt, etc.
      - A.L.S. 4pp., Washington, May 1, 1882 to General Crawford with reference to Fort Sumter. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - A.L.S. 8pp., May 10, 1882, Washington. (Box 1, Folder 3)
        Giving an account of his visit to Fort Sumter, where he was sent to report on the conditions of things generally and to find out how well the provisions would last. Fox was Assistant Secretary of the Navy.
    - Joseph Holt, Secretary of War in Buchanan's Cabinet. A.L.S. 2pp. 8mo., Sunday (December 30, 1860) to General Winfield Scott. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Mentioning President Lincoln; touching on the relief of Fort Pickens, etc.
    - Francis W. Pickens, Governor of South Carolina (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - L.S. 2pp. folio. Headquarters, January 9, 1861, to Lieutenant Colonel Hamilton (Box 1, Folder 3)
        Ordering that the greatest precaution should be taken to prevent the receipt of supplies at Fort Sumter.
      - A.L.S. 7pp. 4to. Charleston, January 23, 1861, to Jefferson Davis. (Box 1, Folder 3)
        Probably the first draft of the letter, endorsed in Pickens' autograph, "Copy of letter to Colonel Davis, Mississippi, January 23, 1861." Giving full details for the defense of Charleston; proposed Davis' selection as Commander-in-Chief of the Confederate forces. Discusses the probable status of the Southern states, should the Union be dissolved.
      - A.L.S. 4pp. 4to, Headquarters, State of South Carolina, February 7, 1861. (Box 1, Folder 3)
        To J. Thompson, Collector of the Port at Charleston. Probably a first draft. An extraordinary letter in which the writer suggests that the way to prevent the inauguration of Lincoln is for the citizens of Maryland and Virginia to sieze Washington.
      - A.L.S. 3pp. folio, Executive Department, State of South Carolina, February 13, 1861. (Box 1, Folder 3)
        To C.G. Memminger, Secretary of the Confederate Treasury. Mentions President Davis, urges that Sumter's surrender be demanded by Davis, predicts Lincoln's administration will fall to pieces, etc.
    - James L. Orr, L.S. 9pp. 4to, Greenville, S.C., September 21, 1871, to General Crawford (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Contains reference to arrangements between President Buchanan and the South Carolina delegation regarding the forts and troops in Charleston harbor.
    - William P. Miles, A.L.S. 8pp. 4to, Montgomery, February 20, 1861, to Governor Pickens (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Proposing that Davis should issue an order to attack Sumter.
  - VOLUME II
    - John A. Campbell, Associate Justice of the Supreme Court
      - A.L.S. 3 pp. 8mo., Washington, April 7, 1861, to Secretary Seward. (Box 1, Folder 4)
        Relating to Fort Sumter and Pickens and his discussions with the South Carolina Commissioners who were negotiating for the surrender of the Fort. First draft of the letter and so endorsed by Campbell. Letter dated April 13, 1861 - Unsigned.
      - A.L.S. 2pp. Washington, April 20, 1861, to Seward (Box 1, Folder 4)
        Enclosing copy of letter sent to Seward in 1861 to which he requests an answer. The first draft of letter endorsed on back by Campbell. Complains of the "systematic duplicity" of the administration.
      - A.L.S. 2pp. Baltimore, April 19, 1888, to General Crawford with reference to the bombardment of Sumter. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - M.S. unsigned. 12pp. folio. (Box 1, Folder 4)
        Relating in detail the events leading up to the bombardment of Fort Sumter. Recites at length the conversation that took place between the commissioners of the Confederacy and Seward.
    - W. Gilmore Simms, A.L.S. 3pp. 4to, Woodlawn, S.C., December 13, 1860. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      To B.J. Lossing, referring to the temper of the people in the South and the prospect of war.
    - Major Robert Anderson, A.L.S. 2pp., New York, April 10. Referring to the defense of Sumter. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - E.B. Anderson (Mrs. Robert Anderson), A.L.S. 2pp., Bridgeport, August 7, 1863. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      To B.J. Lossing, with narrative of Mrs. Anderson's visit to Fort Sumter with Peter Hart. Written in Lossing's hand on 14pp. 4to.
    - Salmon P. Chase, A.L.S., 3pp. 8mo., Providence, August 24, 1866, to B.J. Lossing. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Referring to the question that Lincoln proposed to his Cabinet regarding the provisioning of Fort Sumter and the replies to this inquiry made by Blair and Yates.
    - General David R. Jones, D.S., 2pp. folio. Headquarters Charleston, April 6, 1861. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      General Orders Number 9. Ordering the bombardment of Fort Sumter in case the guns from the Fort open fire.
    - Gustavus V. Fox
      - A.L.S. 5pp. 8mo., Washington November 7, 1864. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - A.L.S. 3pp., January 21, 1865, giving an account of the arrangements regarding Fort Sumter. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - To B.J. Lossing, Washington, January 21, 1865. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - General P.G.T. Beauregard, L.S. 3pp. 4to, New Orleans, July 16, 1870, to General Crawford. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Referring to the conditions of the works on Morris Island, etc., at the time of the bombardment of Fort Sumter.
    - Governor Francis W. Pickens, L.S. 2pp. 4to, State of South Carolina, Headquarters, May 28, 1861. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      To General Beauregard, thanking him for pieces of the flag staff taken from Fort Sumter. Endorsed by General Beauregard.
    - General S.W. Crawford; a series of A.L.S. written to General Beauregard in 1869. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Inquiring about various matters in connection with Fort Sumter. July 12, 22, November 9, November 22, December 4, 1869; all mutilated.
    - General P.G.T. Beauregard; notes dictated to W.A. Marrin about the first and second siege of Fort Sumter; 12pp., folio, in pencil. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Major Robert Anderson, L.S. 4pp., New York City, May 26, 1862. Referring to the part he played in the defense of Fort Sumter. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - General P.G.T. Beauregard, A.L.S. 2pp. 4to, to General Alf Roman August 22, 1882. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Regarding the evacuation of Fort Sumter and the incorrectness of Jefferson Davis' statements regarding the siege.
    - Gist, S.R., A.L.S. to Col. Manigault, April 8, 1861. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Ripley, Roswell S., A.L.S. to Gen. Beauregard, Fort Sumter, May 16, 1861. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - General James H. Trapier, A.L.S. Charleston, January 4, 1861, to Governor Pickens. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Reporting on his examination of the defenses of Fort Moultrie and stating what should be done to capture Fort Sumter.
    - General Gustavus W. Smith, A.L.S. 3pp., New York, March 12, 1861, to General Beauregard (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Stating that Sumter will be evacuated by order of the Federal Government. Smith was at this time state commissioner of New York. He later became a General in the Confederate Army.
    - Pettigrew, James Johnston, A.D.S., Sullivan's Island, April 11, 1861. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Mercer, Samuel. Copies of 3 letters: April 7 [two on this date], 8, 1861. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Admiral Andrew H. Foote, A.L.S. 3pp. 4to, Navy Yard, New York, April 9, 1861, to Gideon Welles, marked private. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      With three letters of Captain Mercer. These letters refer to the controversy caused by the ordering of Lieutenant Porter to the command of the "Politan," the vessel intended to carry supplies to Fort Sumter.
    - Joseph R. Hawley, Governor of Connecticut
      - A.L. Hartford, March 12, 1861, to Gideon Welles, recognizing the necessity of evacuating Sumter. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - A.L.S. 6pp., Hartford, March 27, 1861, referring to the evacuation of Sumter, etc. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Isaac Toucey, Secretary of the Navy under Buchanan. A.L.S. 2pp., Washington, February 14, 1861, to Gideon Welles. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Referring to his support of Anderson.
    - Edwin M. Stanton, A.L.S. 1p. 4to. War Department, Washington, March 28, 1865. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      To General Robert Anderson, enclosing order of the President, directing the flag of the United States to be raised on the Fort on the 4th anniversary of the evacuation of the Fort.
    - William Lloyd Garrison, A.L.S. 4pp. 8mo. Providence, April 13, 1866. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Describing the raising of the flag on Fort Sumter in 1865. Tells of the devastation of Charleston. Recommends the impeachment of Johnson and refers to Lincoln's emancipation of the slaves.
    - Hewett, S.C. 2 A.L.S. to Pres. Lincoln and his cabinet. Boston, April 22, 23, 1861. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Gustavus V. Fox, A.L.S. January 21, 1865, to Benson J. Lossing (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Gist, A.L.S., April 8, 1861, to Col. Manigault. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Dr. S.C. Hewett, 2 A.L.S. 12pp., Boston, April 22-23, 1861. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      To President Lincoln and his Cabinet. Calls General Scott - Major Anderson - traitors. Attacks the President and Secretaries Seward and Chase.
  - VOLUME III
    - Major Robert Anderson, A.L.S. 4pp., Fort Moultrie, S.C., December 15, 1860, to Dr. G.T. Metcalf. (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Written shortly before leaving Fort Moultrie and removed to Fort Sumter: "I would rather not be kept here to surrender when a demand is made for the Fort, I don't like the name of having surrendered.… Having rec'd orders to defend, I felt it my duty to call for an adequate force."
    - General Thomas Jordan, A.L.S. 4pp., November 3, 1861, to General Beauregard (Box 1, Folder 5)
      "The letter which the President is to write, or has written, about the report, will never be sent you, if it was ever written."
    - L.P. Griffin, A.L.S. 4pp., New York March 7 (n.y.) to General Beauregard. (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Congratulating him on his promotion: "What the devil is to be the end of all this? … Fort Sumter will be attacked—Fort Sumter will not be attacked."
    - John Bonner, 4 A.L.S. January 16, 31; February 9, 14, 1861. (Box 1, Folder 5)
      To Dr. Crawford arranging for the publication in Harper's Weekly of interior views of the Fort, etc.
    - Papers relating to Fort Sumter 1860 to 1861. Returns of Ordnance, etc. (7 items) (Box 1, Folder 5)
- POLITICAL ASSOCIATES OF LINCOLN
  All bound in full levant.
  - Horace Greeley, A.L.S. 1p. 8mo., New York, October 24, 1861, to Caleb B. Smith (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Stating that Lincoln had never consulted him in regard to cabinet appointments.
  - John Hay, A.L.S. 2pp. 4to, Washington, March 15, 1861. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Referring to Lincoln's refusal to make recommendations for departmental appointments.
  - Henry J. Raymond, journalist. A.L.S. 6pp. 8mo, New York, August 11, 1864. (Box 2, Folder 6)